2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com
E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



CURRICULUM VITAE

SRA Locum Template

It is of importance that all our CVs are received in the same format. We appreciate if you could fill this template out and return to <u>info@sralocum.com</u>. Should you have any questions please contact: Shahid Ali, Locum Coordination Consultant, SRA Locum (00353 1 685 4700).

RESUME FOR THE POST OF ORTHOPAEDIC REGISTRAR

Bio-data

Name : HASNAIN RAZA

Age : 43 years

DOB : 3rd July 1979

Nationality : Pakistani/ Irish Current Address : Dublin. Ireland



Personal Statement

I am an accomplished orthopaedic surgeon with more than 16 years relevant orthopaedic experience including 4 years Residency and 11 years post FCPS experience in Ireland.

I have done one year Paediatric Orthopaedic Fellowship from the largest children Hospital in Ireland and currently I am doing one year clinical Fellowship in Hip and Knee surgery from Beacon Hospital Dublin which is ending in July 2023. Both fellowships are accreditted from the Royal College of Surgeons Ireland.

I worked more than 5 years in Tallaght University Hospital (TUH), Dublin, a major trauma centre and the only hospital in Ireland where pelvic and acetabular injuries are referred and treated.

My professional journey started in 1997 as a medical student from Dow Medical College Karachi, Pakistan. After medical internship in 2003 from Aga Khan Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan (AKUH), I did basic surgical training followed by orthopaedic residency from AKUH. I passed

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5 W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



my orthopaedic fellowship exit exam FCPS in 2010 from College of Physicians and Surgeons Pakistan (CPSP)

I moved to Ireland in 2011, to gain further experience in different sub-specialities of orthopaedics. I worked in various major trauma centres and elective orthopaedic hospitals across Ireland as a **Registrar** and **Fellow**, where I was involved in management of various emergency and elective orthopaedic conditions including fracture fixations, arthroplasties, sports related injuries, deformities correction, musculoskeletal infections, Foot and Ankle surgery and Paediatric Orthopaedics.

I am highly dedicated to provide safe, efficient and patient centered care. I keep myself updated with the latest technological advancements in the field of orthopaedic surgery and applying those in the clinical practice.

Education:

M.B;B.S	Dow Medical College, Karachi, Pakistan	2002
MCPS Surgery	Member College of Physicians and Surgeons Pakistan	2008
FCPS Orthopedic	Fellow College of Physicians and Surgeons Pakistan	2010
MRCS	Member Royal College of Surgeons Ireland	2013
FEBOT	Fellow European Board of Orthopedic and Traumatology	2013
Fellowship Paediatric Orthopaedics Royal College of Surgeons Ireland		2019

Registration/ Medical Licence:

Pakistan Medical and Dental Council (PM&DC). Since 2002

Irish Medical Council (IMC) Since Sept, 2011

General Medical Council (UK) Since May 2014

Experience

Hip and Knee Surgery Fellow

Beacon Hospital Dublin, Ireland. July 2022 to date

Orthopaedic Registrar

Tallaght University Hospital, Dublin Jan 2022 to July 2022

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



Registrar Paediatric Orthopaedics Jan 2021 to Jan 2022

Children Hospital Ireland in Crumlin, Dublin, Ireland

Orthopaedic Registrar

Tallaght University Hospital, Dublin July 2019 to Jan 2021

Paediatric Orthopaedic Fellowship (One Year)

Our Lady's Hospital for Sick Children, Crumlin, July 2018 to July 2019

Dublin (Accredited by Royal College of Surgeons Ireland)

Registrar Orthopaedics.

Our Lady's Hospital for Sick Children, Crumlin, 7th Jan 2018 July 2018

Dublin.

Registrar Orthopaedics.

Adelaide and Meath Hospital, Tallaght, Dublin 14th July 2014 to 6th Jan 2018

Registrar Orthopaedics.

Our Lady's Hospital, Navan, and Our Lady of Lourdes

Hospital, Drogheda, Ireland. Sept 2011 to July 2014

Clinical Instructor Orthopaedics

Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan. Jan 2011 to July 2011

Resident, Orthopaedics

Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan Nov 2006 to Dec 2010

Resident, General Surgery

Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan Nov. 2004 to Oct 2006

Honorary Research Officer, Deptt. of Surgery

Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan May to June 2004

Internship

Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi. Nov. 2002 to Oct. 2003

Nominated for The Best Intern.

Elective Clinical Rotations

Clinical Observer in Orthopaedic Department of Our Lady of Lourdes Hospital,
 Drogheda, Ireland from 19th July 2011 to 12th Sept 2011.

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5 W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



- Visiting Registrar in Indus Hospital, Karachi, Pakistan under supervision of Prof. M. Amin Chinoy, FRCS, Head of Orthopedic Department, from May 10th till 12th June 2010.
- Elective Final year medical student in Shaukat Khanum Memorial Cancer Hospital and Research Centre, Lahore, Pakistan under supervision of Dr. Shaikh Moin-ul-Haq, MRCP, Dept. of Medicine from Sept. 2nd till 25th 2002.

Presentations

- Presented in 34th International Pak Orthocon in Karachi, Pakistan on Upper Limb controversies in radial head fractures on 13th November 2021.
- Presented 'Outcome of Ilizarov Hip reconstruction osteotomy' in 6th ASAMI in Cairo, Egypt on 16th June 2010.
- Presented 'Outcome of Hip reconstruction osteotomy by Ilizarov' in 23rd International Orthopedic Conference **(Orthocon-09)** in Lahore, 2009
- Presented 'Outcome of Arthroscopic meniscal repair with inside-out technique, an AKU Hospital experience' in 22nd International Orthopedic Conference (Orthocon-08) in Karachi, Pakistan in 2008

Publications

- Kunal Mohan, Patrick McCabe, Wafi Mohammad, Hasnain Raza, Brendan O'Daly, Michael Leonard. Impact of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Pelvic and Acetabular Trauma: Experiences From a National Tertiary Referral Centre. Cureus 2021 June 22;13(6)
- Peter Dawson, Lisa Dunne, **Hasnain Raza** et al. Total Hip Arthroplasty for the treatment of osteoarthritis secondary to acetabular fractures treated by open reduction and internal fixation. Eur J Orthop Surg Taumatol 2019 Jul;29(5):1049-1054.
- Raval P, Ramasamy A, Raza H, Khan K. Comparison of Short Vs Long Proximal Femoral Nail Antirotation, in Treating Pertrochanteric fractures. Malaysian Orthopaedic Journal 2016, Volume 10, No. 1.
- H.Raza, A.Bowe, N.Davarinos, M.Leonard. Bowel preparation prior to percutaneous ilio-sacral screw insertion: is it necessary? Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. DOI 10.1007/s00068-016-0704. Published 4th July 2016.
- Hasnain Raza, Anant Mahapatra. Acute compartment syndrome in Orthopedics: Causes, Diagnosis and Management, A Review article. Advances in Orthopedics. Volume 2015, Article ID 543412

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com

E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



- Mujeeb Rohilla, Khalid Khan, Hasnain Raza. Musculoskeletal Manifestations of Atypical Mycobacterium: Case Reports. Surgical Science, 2014, 5, 25-27
- Umer M, Rashid H, Umer HM, Raza H. Hip reconstruction osteotomy by Ilizarov method as a salvage option for abnormal hip joints. Biomed Res Int. 2014; 835681
- Raza H, Hashmi P, Bifocal metachronous giant cell tumor of ulna and distal radius. J
 Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2014 Mar;24 suppl 1: S41-2
- Kashif Abbas, Hasnain Raza, Masood Umer. Effect of early tourniquet release in total knee arthroplasty. JCPSP 2013, Vol. 23(8): 00
- Kashif Abbas, Pervaiz Hashmi, Hasnain Raza "Short term results of ligament reconstruction and tendon interposition (LRTI) resection arthroplasty for thumb basal joint arthritis". J Pak Med Assoc., Vol. 62, No.4, April 2012.
- Hasnain Raza, Pervaiz Hashmi, Kamran Hafeez. Functional and Anatomical Outcome of Minimally Invasive Plate Osteosynthesis Technique for Tibial Plateau Fractures. Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery 2012;20(1)42-7
- Hasnain Raza, Kashif Abbas, Masood Umer. 'Outcome of Arthroscopic meniscal repair with inside-out technique', J Pak Med Assoc., Vol. 61, No. 1, January 2011. (Index Journal)

Research in Progress

- To examine the response of patients to a video technology based shared decision-making (SDM) process in a prospective total hip replacement cohort.
 Hasnain Raza, Anthony Pierce, Turlough O'Donnell. (Randomised Control Trial)
- Medial Vs Lateral Uni compartmental Knee replacement in patients up to sixty years of age.

Teaching Experience

- Currently taking Orthopaedic teaching sessions weekly for undergraduate medical students of University College Dublin Ireland, as Fellow since July 2022.
- Participated in Undergraduate Medical Student examinations, contributed in preparing orthopedic teaching material, delivered orthopedic teaching sessions for undergraduate students in Aga Khan University Hospital as Instructor orthopedics.

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com
E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



Courses/Workshops/Conferences

- Participant in Basic Life Support by Irish Heart Foundation/ American Heart Association held in Beacon Hospital, Dublin, Ireland on 15th August 2022.
- Basic Emergency Ultrasound Course, Royal College of Surgeons Ireland, 4th November 2021.
- AO Trauma Course, Advanced principles of fracture Management, 10-13th November 2015 Basingstoke, UK.
- Participant in The Cambridge Basic Orthopedic Science Course held on 18th 20th
 March 2015
- Participant in The Knee arthroplasty course organized by PALACADEMY in Dublin on 14th – 15th October 2014.
- Participant in Irish Residence Trauma Course in Upper Limb held in Royal College of Surgeons, Dublin, Ireland on 28th April 2012.
- Participant in Radiation Protection and Technique Course held in Mater University Hospital, Dublin, Ireland on 17th November 2011.
- Participant in workshop on Spinal Manual Handling in Spinal Cord Injury held in Our Lady of Lourdes Hospital, Drogheda, Ireland on 25th July, 2011.
- Participant in workshop on **Instrumentation in spinal trauma** held in March 2011 in Neurotrauma Conference at AKUH.
- Advance Trauma Life Support (ATLS) from CPSP in collaboration with American College of Surgeons Nov 2010.
- Participant in 3rd Pelvic and Acetabular surgery Course held in July 2010 at Aga Khan University Hospital, Karachi.
- Participant in 6th AKU Ilizarov Course held in February 2010 at Aga Khan University Hospital Karachi.

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.sralocum.com E: info@sralocum.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



- AO Course on Principles of Operative Fracture Management at Aga Khan University, Nov 2008
- CME Workshop on Brachial Plexus Injuries at Aga Khan University, Oct 2008
- Hand surgery workshop by Pakistan Orthopaedics Association, at Aga Khan University, Aug 2007
- Orthopaedic Oncology Course by Pakistan Orthopaedic Association at Aga Khan University, April 2007

Miscellaneous

- Actively undertook fieldwork of mass vaccination campaigns at Polio days and "Monitoring of National Immunization days, October, 2000 in Karachi, Pakistan.
- Coordinated monthly 'Mortality and Morbidity' meetings of orthopedic section of Aga Khan Hospital from 1st Nov. 2009 till 31st December 2010.

Referees:

Available on Request.